TOMAS LOZANO

Phone: 343 777 6214 ■ Email: tomaslozanol@gmail.com

Highly motivated web and app developer with additional experience in business administration. A fast-learner with strong interpersonal and leadership skills who is particularly well versed in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Python and SQL. Current projects include a mobile app and a Python-based web scrapper.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, Python Frameworks/Libraries/CMS: Bootstrap, ¡Query, JSON,

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, WordPress, React

XML, Sass Databases: MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB Back-end: PHP Others: Android Studio, GitHub, Jira

Experience

IT Customer Service (Contract)

FOKO RETAIL – Ottawa, ON, Jul 2020 – Sep 2020

- Created database-searching scripts using MongoDB and JavaScript to reduce inefficiencies in daily tasks
- Actively supported the launch of a new operating system by receiving, evaluating and solving customer issues using Jira
- Integrated updates to the new operating system into a user manual for clients, explaining technical instructions clearly and concisely to end users on mobile or desktop

Front-End Web Developer (Co-Op)

PATIO CONCEPTS INC. - Ottawa, ON, Jan 2018 - May 2018

- Independently redesigned the website by integrating new designs and improving the user experience using HTML5,
 CSS3 and JavaScript
- Directly improved the company website's speed by 15%, through careful evaluation of inefficiencies in the code, and by implementing their remedies using HTML5 and Bootstrap

Quotation Engineer

TPI S.A. - Santiago, Chile, Oct 2015 - Aug 2016

 Identified inquiries from potential clients, reviewed project scope, provided engineering quotes and finalized deals for clients in the mining and stainless-steel metal industry

Marketing, Web Analyst

SIG SIG S.A. – Santiago, Chile, Jan 2013 – Sep 2015

- Reduced merchandise cost 25% by conducting a systematic review of current providers and an analysis of alternate options
- Implemented internet marketing strategy Search Engine Optimization (SEO) to improve website visibility and raising potential clients visits by a 10%

Education

ALGONQUIN COLLEGE - Ottawa, Canada

Diploma in Computer Programming, Sep 2016 – Dec 2018

DEL DESARROLLO UNIVERSITY - Santiago, Chile

Bachelor's Business Administration Engineering, Mar 2005 – Jul 2010

Portfolio: tomaslozano.github.io/